leadloans.co.uk 2016-05-16

# Privacy Policy - Direct Pay Day Loans Lender In UK

##  [ Privacy Policy](http://leadloans.co.uk/index.php/privacy-policy-1)

In this day and age it's extremely important for companies to keep tight control of their clients personal information. We are a registered data controller under the Data Protection Act and, as such, are duty bound to keep your data safe and secure at all times.

Our Privacy Policy applies to all of our customers, both past and present. We reserve the right to update or amend this policy at any time, with or without notice.

Consent

Simply by registering with us you are consenting for us to use and disclose your personal information to our select third parties, who may contact you by electronic means about their products and services. Additionally you agree to our placing cookies on the computer or other device you are using to apply.

Keeping it Safe

We keep your information safe by using secure socket layer (SSL) encryption technology and with a strict need-to-know employee code. Data is stored in encrypted electronic form, with firewalls and other advanced technologies to prevent unauthorised access. These are constantly being updated and tested to ensure security is maintained. Lastly we also comply fully with UK data protection laws.

Your data

This is collected from both your applications and from outside sources, such a credit agencies and customer service providers.

Additionally we may collect information about your computer, including your IP address, operating system and browser. This is used for statistical data collection only and it will not identify individuals. We may obtain information about your internet usage by using a cookie file, which will be stored on your hard drive - again without identifying any individual. Cookies are used to store users' browsing preferences. For details about cookies please visit: http://www.allaboutcookies.org.

Browsers can be set to refuse cookies but this will mean you may not get full use of the site, or enjoy specific offers. As part of our quality checks, and staff training, calls are recorded and monitored. Recordings may also be used to combat fraud.

We may sell or share the data submitted, with third parties involved in providing our service. All of these companies are bound by the same rules and principles that we are, with regard to your information.

As the data controller we may use the information that identifies you (personal data) for statistical analysis, to develop and improve our products, update your data and determine which of our other products might be of interest to you; assess lending and insurance risks; arrange, underwrite and administer insurance and handling claims; identify, detect and tackle fraud, money laundering and other crime; carry out regulatory checks; keeping you informed about your loan, for market research, and for the products and services offered to third parties.

Your personal data remains confidential, only supplying it for the reasons mentioned above. This includes:

Our employees, agents and subcontractors in their duties of operating our lending business and obtaining payments.  
Sharing information though an organisation providing a centralised application matching service, collecting from and about mortgage and/or credit applications - for preventing and detecting fraud  
To licenced credit brokers in the case your application with leadloans is declined, and we believe they may be able to assist you.  
By submitting your details you are agreeing to the terms of this privacy policy, consenting to the use and disclosure of your personal data as described herein. When you apply for a loan with leadloans we will check records held about you (and others, if applicable), namely:

Our records  
Credit Reference Agencies (CRA')  
Fraud prevention agencies (FPAs)  
Credit Reference Agencies (CRAs)

When CRAs receive a search request from us, in response for a loan application, they will place a search footprint of your credit file that may be seen by other providers. They will supply public (including electoral role) and shared credit and fraud prevention information. CRAs will record information sent to them.

Our checks will include assessing applications for credit and verifying identities of clients to prevent/detect fraud, money laundering and other crimes. We reserve the right to make searches as and when required with CRAs and FPAs to manage your account.

Details of how you manage your account will be provided to CRA's. This includes information on whether you do not repay in full or on the time agreed. The CRAs will record all details, such as how long the debt has been outstanding and whether it remains so. This information may be supplied to other organisations, who may carry out similar checks and take action to trace your whereabouts and recover any outstanding debts. Records remain on file for 6 years, after they are closed - whether settled or defaulted.

If you are making a joint application we will link your records together, consequently you must have their prior agreement to disclose information about them. CRAs also link records together and these links will remain, until you or your partner/s files for disassociation with the CRAs to break that link.

Your data may also be used for other purposes for which you give your permission or, in very limited circumstances, when required by law or where permitted under the terms of the Data Protection Act 1998.

If your application is not completed we will hold on to your data for a maximum of 30 days, in case you wish to resume the process within this period.

Under the Data Protection Act 1998, you have a right to access certain personal records held by ourselves, CRAs and FPAs about you. This is a "subject access request". You can make this by writing to leadloans. There may be a charge for this but this will not be levied until you've been told the amount, what it's for and you have told us that you wish to proceed.

Should you provide false or inaccurate information and we have reasonable grounds to suspect fraud (or we identify fraud) we will pass this information to fraud prevention agencies and it may also be passed onto other organisations involved in fraud and other crime prevention. We and other organisations may also access and use such information to prevent fraud and money laundering, for example, when:

Checking applications details for credit, credit related or other facilities  
Managing credit, credit related accounts or facilities  
Recovering debt  
Checking details on proposals and claims for all types of insurance  
Checking details of job applicants and employees.  
Should you wish to receive details of the relevant fraud prevention agencies, please contact us at leadloans. We and other organisations may access and use other countries' information recorded by fraud prevention agencies.

Contact From leadloans And Approved Third Parties

During your application you may have ticked "yes" to being contacted with regard to products and services. Should you no longer wish this service you can log into your account and change your preferences at any time, or follow the instructions on the messages received.

We only partner with trusted companies, who agree to respect any request to unsubscribe from marketing communications. However, we are not responsible for managing that process or any disputes.

Third Party Links

Our site may contain links to third party websites. Should you follow any of these links please note that they have their own terms and privacy policies; we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these. By registering at leadloans you may receive communications from third party companies. While working with selected partners, we're not responsible for their services or representations.

Restrictions

To register with us you must be 18-years of age, or older.
